How about it?
Found anything good?
No, no such luck...
That won't do. You've got to fend for yourself here.
Thank you very much.
However, are you sure about this?
We are...
Looking at your skin and eyes, I can tell.
You're people from Ishbal, right?
This is a gathering place for
those who, for whatever reason,
cannot live in the lands of their birth.
We've got petty criminals and corrupt soldiers
who have been found out and ousted here as well.
Laughable, isn't it?
Here, have a drink.
A-An Ishbalan with a scar on his face!
I've heard about this guy before!
Wait! Hey, wait up!
Wait up, I say!
I'm sorry for popping off
at you like that!
He merged himself with the wall?!
Hey, you!
Dammit!
Jeez, I'm in a hurry here.
Well?
They say that despite
being a State Alchemist,
you have an interest in
the Philosopher's Stone.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Ham, 100 grams, 128 cens.
I'd like to see someone named Izumi.
Chicken breasts, 160 cens.
The Elric brothers wouldn't have come visiting here, would they?
Do you know them?
Please do something about them.
No way! I don't know what that person has in mind!
Besides, right now,
Ed and Al are probably in trouble.
Sliced beef chuck, 200 cens.
We are here on military business.
There is no need to hide anything.
Mixed ground beef and pork, 98 cens.
Allow me...
Wait, Major! Ed...
Huh?
It looks like a friendship has been born out of their muscles, huh?
What the?
So, where are the
two of them, miss?
What are you talking about?
There are stories floating around about how you used your brother as an experimental subject
and transmuted only his spirit.
Or how you're being
pursued by homunculi.
I'm offering to take you
someplace safe!
Both you and your
freak of a brother!
What did you say
his brother was?
He really is hollow!
Just like Tucker said!
Tucker-san?!
Why, you!
Don't get so upset
over what people say!
You're not getting away!
Magnificent!
However...
I'm magnificent as well.
What was that thing?
A Chimera?
Don't tell me he escaped from the 5th Laboratory.
Oh, Major! It's been a while.
Mm-hmm.
This is Lt. Colonel Archer.
He is in charge of the
Court-Martial Office.
Why are you out here
in the countryside?
Court-Martial Office?
Just like Lt. Colonel Hughes, right?
Is the Lt. Colonel doing all right?
I'd like to ask you about that Chimera, as well as several other things.
Sorry, but now is not the time.
Let's go.
Yeah.
This is starting to get interesting, is it not?
A perfect Chimera, huh?
I want him.
Huh?
"Huh?" doesn't cover it!
How come mine are different from yours, Ed and Al?
This isn't my real arm and leg.
Then what happened to your real ones, Ed?
Where are they?
Say, do you remember
where you got this scar from?
I don't know where.
Maybe it is just a coincidence after all.
How could that be?
But, Brother, your arm and leg were
carried away in an equivalent exchange, right?
Why would they be here?
It's just too weird.
Yeah, it's weird. That's for sure.
But you know, supposing that
my arm and leg were brought back from behind that doorway, then maybe...
your body, too, could be...
Take a close look at the sole of his right foot.
We're getting closer to the mystery of the 5th Laboratory.
Let's seize him.
Are we not taking the brothers?
We've got ourselves
an even bigger catch.
Do it.
Say, have I done anything wrong?
Brother!
What do you think
you're doing, Major?!
Brother, no!
Major, that boy doesn't have any memory!
We've already filed a report!
He's an important witness to the
destructive activities that took place in Central.
We'll question him at the
Southern Command Center.
What are you talking about?
You've seen this crest
before too, haven't you?
That boy is in league
with the homunculi?
He's connected to the persons who destroyed the 5th Laboratory.
Major!
Edward Elric, we're going to have to retake your testimonies as well.
Wait for us at
your master's house.
Wasn't continuing this investigation prohibited by the Führer?
A long time ago,
I was bitten by a fox.
Right here.
That boy has the same scar
on his shoulder.
What's more, that leg of his
doesn't appear to be his own.
Are you saying that boy's arm and leg
are yours?
How could that be?
I don't know.
That's why I want to verify it.
Give it up.
We can't!
This is the reason why Brother and I have been struggling all this time!
And if you look into it—actually,
I don't know how you would look into it—
but if you did find out that that is your brother's arm and leg, what would you do?
Pluck them off,
and claim them for your own?
Don't be ridiculous!
In that case, you're better off
not finding out.
Yoki... Yoki...
I've heard that name before somewhere.
He said himself that he was once in charge of a mine in the east.
Ah, I remember now.
Yes, it's true!
It's the honest truth!
Y-Yes, that's right!
That is wonderful.
If it's true, then I will inform the Führer.
He would probably allow you to return to the military.
Yahoo!
So then, the place they took him to was, get this, the Southern Command Center!
That's great. Nice work.
Way to find him.
Forget about the brothers for a while,
and keep an eye on him.
Got that?
It sounds like the Elric brothers are just like you said.
Y-Yes...
I'm sure the two of them
will be of use to you.
I hear that Envy and Pride and them are after them,
so it sounded like it would be fun
to make off with them.
But thanks to them, it looks like we'll be able to come by something even better.
To think that there would be a homunculus with the ability to use alchemy, like me...
I'll have to get him on my side, or things will be more troublesome down the road.
Please let me go after him.
Dumbass.
You think this is someplace that you can just get away with haphazardly busting into?
You guys are former soldiers, so you should understand.
I was once posted to the
Southern Command Center.
Don't go butting in where you
aren't needed, State Alchemist.
No, maybe we can have him at least show the other two the way.
However, if you try to betray us...
Please, suit yourself.
I just want to see some fireworks again.
What did you do with that boy?!
We haven't done anything.
Sensei, why are you so particular about that boy, anyhow?
The military might be able to find out who he is.
Besides, that boy is...
Al!
...not human.
You may not believe it,
but we've met homunculi—created people.
They all had powers that
normal humans could not possess.
Like a mouth that could eat any kind of metal,
fingers that could penetrate anything,
and the ability to
transform their body at will.
That boy did use alchemy,
but he's still some kind of monster.
Do you know why
a homunculus is born?
Izumi-san...
Did you think that I hadn't realized what that boy was?
Izumi-san!
Sensei!
She's been like this for that long?
Mm-hmm.
But she's so strong that
it always slips our minds.
What kind of illness is it?
It's possible that the hospitals in Central might be able to cure—
Unfortunately, it would probably be too difficult for them.
Why is that?
I hate to say it, but rather than
treating her in a rural hospital like this—
It's an incurable illness, isn't it?
Her organs from here
to about here are gone.
Gone?
It's like they were completely cut out from her.
And the remaining organs are intricately linked to each other, maintaining their functions.
I don't even know how it is
that she's holding on to her life.
Brother, that means...
It almost sounds like they were carried away, huh?
Then, Sensei did the
same thing that we did.
Doctor!
Thanks, dear,
but I'm all right.
I'm going alone.
I wasn't able to do anything for you before, either.
Which is why...
Please... I don't want you to see...
what I'm about to do.
Sig-san!
Is Izumi-san inside there?
Why won't you tell me anything?
Neither will Izumi-san
nor Ed nor Al...
Why?!
I didn't know anything.
She told me she was sorry.
I was the one who chose to keep her from giving birth, in order to save her life.
And yet she told me
she was sorry that
she wasn't able to give birth,
over and over again.
Your baby?
Is that so?
But I didn't know...
her sorrow...
or how hard she was taking it.
I never thought she would do
something like that on her own.
Something like what?
The same thing
that Ed and Al did.
Human transmutation?
She tried to bring
the baby back to life?
She did everything by herself.
I don't know
what she saw there.
Just that when she came back,
the insides of her belly were completely gone,
and she said she would never
be able to have children again.
And when she said that,
she told me
she was sorry again.
It's up to you, mad bomber.
I might be a little
short on sulfur here.
What was that explosion?
Major, seize that woman!
Major!
Well, well...
It's certainly festive here, huh?
Sensei...
Please put that boy down and get out of here.
Sensei, I am still
a dog of the military!
Why would the Führer be here?
That lizard bastard!
Pardon me, but we have
a slight interest in that boy too.
Among Sensei, the Major,
not to mention these guys...
Damn. A four-way standoff, is it?
No, it's a five-way standoff.
That man just now...
Was he not of
the people of Ishbal?
Do not approach him.
Did you not notice
the tattoo on his face?
He is a transgressor.
He has disobeyed God's teachings
and has been eternally cast out of Ishbal.
A group of Ishbalan people, in the south, in Kishua?
It is believed that
Scar is among them.
You understand, don't you?
Yes, sir!
We're moving out!
Scar is in hiding in the western slums of the city of Kishua.
If he surrenders quietly,
that will be fine.
If he resists, we will take him down, along with the slum's inhabitants.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 31: "Sin"
Give them back.
Those belong to Brother.
Getting those back is the reason why we've been traveling!